(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
あくあ色すーぱーみらくる☆どり〜む♪
Aqua-iro Super Miracle Dream
YOUTUBE LIVE 開催決定！
YouTube Live Confirmed!
2021.05.09 21:00~
メイドの日（5月10日）を記念した3Dライブ！
A 3D live to commemorate Maid Day (May 10th)!
ご主人様への感謝を込めて
With gratitude to my masters
ガチ歌ライブをYOUTUBEでお届け！
Bringing you a serious singing live on YouTube!
AQUA Ch. 100万人達成！
AQUA Ch. reached 1 million subscribers!
湊あくあ
Minato Aqua
湊あくあです
This is Minato Aqua.
メールが届きましたよ、皆さん
A mail has arrived, everyone!
記念3D LIVE!!
Commemorative 3D LIVE!!
ご主人、ゲームしよ！
Master, let's play a game!
10!
9!
8!
7!
6!
5!
4!
3!
2!
1!
For The Win-Win-Win For The Win-Win-Win
信じててね 大丈夫
For the Win-Win-Win, For the Win-Win-Win
Please believe in me, it'll be okay
あくあ色に染めるよ 君と歩くこの未来を
I'll dye it in Aqua-color, this future I walk with you
自分らしさはどこだろう 自分なりに探しても
Where is my true self? Even if I search in my own way
上手くいかない事だらけよ 仕方ないな
It's full of things that don't go well, but it can't be helped
空回りしちゃって 失敗して 笑われたって
頑張って頑張って ここにいる
Even if I spin my wheels, fail, and get laughed at,
I'm doing my best, doing my best, and I'm right here
君も同じだよ 諦めなきゃきっと掴めるから
You're the same too, if you don't give up, I'm sure you can grasp it
For The Win-Win-Win For The Win-Win-Win
夢は叫べば 今ここで
For the Win-Win-Win, For the Win-Win-Win
If you shout out your dreams, right here and now
叶えたいものは何？ 一つ教えてよ
What is it you want to fulfill? Tell me one thing
For The Win-Win-Win For The Win-Win-Win
信じるだけ 出来るでしょ
For the Win-Win-Win, For the Win-Win-Win
Just believe, you can do it, right?
走り出したその先は あくあ色の未来を
Beyond where you've started running is an Aqua-colored future
A！ Q！ U！ A！
A! Q! U! A!
行くよ レッツゴー！ Fight me!
Here I go, let's go! Fight me!
A！ Q！ U！ A！
A! Q! U! A!
Yes! あくあ For The Win!
Yes! Aqua, For The Win!
伝えるのは下手だから 誤解しないで聞いてよね
I'm not good at expressing myself, so please listen without misunderstanding
私なりの応援だから 分かるでしょ？
It's my own way of cheering, you understand, right?
ねえ 笑ったって泣いたって 一度きり
頑張って頑張って ここに来た
Hey, whether laughing or crying, you only live once
I did my best, did my best, and came here
君がいなきゃ絶対 辿り着けなかった場所だから
Because this is a place I never could have reached without you
For The Win-Win-Win For The Win-Win-Win
今度はギュッと 私から
For the Win-Win-Win, For the Win-Win-Win
This time, I'll give you a tight hug
君の背中を押すよ 強く優しくね
I'll push you forward, strongly yet gently
For The Win-Win-Win For The Win-Win-Win
前を向いて 最後まで
For the Win-Win-Win, For the Win-Win-Win
Look forward, until the very end
見たことのない世界 一緒に旅しようよ
Let's travel together to a world we've never seen before
みんなー！
Everyone!
今日は3Dライブ見に来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to see the 3D live today!
銀河一アイドル湊あくあ、いっぱい歌うから
The universe's #1 idol, Minato Aqua, will be singing a lot
みんなたくさんコメントしてね！
So please leave lots of comments!
よかったら「A-Q-U-A」のところ、コメントで
If you'd like, during the "A-Q-U-A" part
「A-Q-U-A！あくあしか勝たん！」って言ってね！
please comment "A-Q-U-A! Aqua's the best!"
負けたくない悔し涙が 溢れた日ですらも
Even the days when tears of frustration overflowed because I didn't want to lose
無駄じゃない 自分らしさを創ってく
Weren't in vain, they go on to create who I am
だから 大丈夫大丈夫 心配ないよ
大丈夫大丈夫 全力で
So it's okay, it's okay, no need to worry
It's okay, it's okay, with everything I've got
走り抜けたんだ 君なら出来るさ
I ran through it all, you can do it too
喜びも悲しみも 分かち合える人がいる
There are people I can share both joy and sadness with
初めて気づいたんだ 一人じゃないんだって
I realized for the first time that I'm not alone
For The Win-Win-Win For The Win-Win-Win
あなた達と叶えたい
For the Win-Win-Win, For the Win-Win-Win
I want to fulfill it with all of you
夢はきっとこの場所で あくあ色に輝く
My dream will surely shine in Aqua-color right here
A！ Q！ U！ A！
A! Q! U! A!
行くよ レッツゴー！ Fight me!
Here I go, let's go! Fight me!
A！ Q！ U！ A！
A! Q! U! A!
Yes! あくあ For The Win!
Yes! Aqua, For The Win!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ダメじゃない できないんだ どや！
It's not that I'm bad at it, I just can't do it! Hah!
あっちこっちそっちで噂の駄目天使
The useless angel rumored here, there, and everywhere
ダメな子ほどもっと手間暇パワーで補って
The more useless the child, the more time and effort power is needed to compensate
足りないの もっともっと あなたに気に入ってほしい
It's not enough, I want you to like me more and more
だけど自意識が腐れすぎからビビるディスコミュニケーション
But my self-consciousness is so rotten, I'm scared of discommunication
天使のリングの点滅は消えかけてるけど
The flashing of my angel ring is fading out
見方を変えればこれもアイデンティティさ
But from another perspective, this is also my identity
なんて強がりさ 本当は曖昧な愛の感情も
What a bluff, actually even these vague feelings of love...
あなたと探したいの
I want to search for them with you
ねえ 駄目駄目駄目駄目なあたしを愛してね
Hey, please love me, even though I'm so useless
怠惰・哀傷・自堕落・無気力な天使ですが
I'm a lazy, sorrowful, depraved, and lethargic angel, but...
ドキドキドキドキをあげるよ あなたには
I'll give you heart-throbbing excitement
ちゃんと見ていてくれるなら やるよたぶん
If you watch me properly, I'll do it... maybe
ダダダダ 駄目天使は ダダダダ 駄目ですか？
A da-da-da-da useless angel, is that da-da-da-da bad?
だけどあたしはいいか？ やんない・じゃない・できないんだぞ
But am I okay? I won't do it, not that, I just can't!
や！
Ya!
テストでいい点取りたい でも頭がちっとも追いつかない
I want to get good grades on tests, but my brain can't keep up at all
日曜日だって早起きしたい 深夜のネトゲがやめられない
I want to wake up early on Sundays too, but I can't stop playing online games late at night
やる気がないとかそんなんじゃない やる気はあってもできない性分
It's not that I lack motivation, it's just my nature that I can't do it even if I have it
しょうがないなって許してよ エンジェルリングを放り投げながら
Forgive me, saying "it can't be helped", as I toss away my angel ring
天使の翼は使ってない 飛ぶのが怖いから
I don't use my angel wings because I'm afraid of flying
本気を出したら飛べますか？ みたいな顔はしている
I'm making a face like, "Could I fly if I tried my best?"
そんなハリボテの裏側に隠したアイの感情が
Behind that facade, the feelings of love I've hidden...
あなたに笑ってほしいの
Want to see you smile
ねえ 駄目駄目駄目駄目なあたしでいいですか？
Hey, is it okay if I'm so useless?
実際は一切の自信もないような天使ですが
Actually, I'm an angel who doesn't have any confidence at all, but...
クルクルクルクルと巡る頭の中では
Inside my head, which is spinning around and around...
あなたのことばかり考えてるんだ
I'm thinking only about you
駄目駄目駄目駄目なあたしを愛してよ
Love me, even though I'm so useless
もらっちゃえとパッと思うよ 天使だから
I'll just take it, I thought, because I'm an angel
ドキドキドキドキをあげるよ あなたには
I'll give you heart-throbbing excitement
もっと好きになってくれるなら やるよたぶん
If you'll like me even more, I'll do it... maybe
ダダダダ 駄目天使は ダダダダ 駄目ですか？
A da-da-da-da useless angel, is that da-da-da-da bad?
だけどあたしはいいか？ やんない・じゃない・できないんだぞ
But am I okay? I won't do it, not that, I just can't!
ヤ！でも努力はします！
Ya! But I'll try my best!
ヤ！
Ya!
改めまして！
Once again!
皆さんどうも、こんあくあー！
Hello everyone, Kon-Aqua!
湊あくあです！
I'm Minato Aqua!
いやね、早速飛ばしていきましたが
Well, I've been going full speed from the start
みんな、ついてこれてる？
Everyone, can you keep up?
イェーイ！
Yay!
大丈夫かな？
Are you guys okay?
まぁ今日ね、この3Dライブ
Well, today, for this 3D live...
えー企画したのは
Um, the reason I planned this was...
1月にYouTubeチャンネル登録者数が
in January, my YouTube subscriber count...
ありがたいことに100万人を突破いたしまして
thankfully exceeded 1 million people!
そちらの記念というか、ね
This is a commemoration of that, you know?
えーと配信、記念配信っていう感じで
Um, like a commemorative broadcast
やらせていただきました
I'm holding this event
ありがとねみんな！
Thank you everyone!
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much
でもね、あっという間に5月になっちゃったけども
But, it's already May in the blink of an eye
まぁでもね、歌にダンスに
Well, but, with singing and dancing...
それになんかいっぱい、こうセットとかもね
and also lots of things, like the set...
すっごいね、いい感じになってて
it's really turned out great
すごいね、こう力を蓄えてきたので
I've been storing up a lot of energy for this
よかったら最後まで楽しんでってもらえたらなって
So I hope you'll enjoy it until the very end
思ってるよ
I'm looking forward to it
よろしくね、また待っててくれてありがとね
Please enjoy, and thanks for waiting for me
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ということで
And so...
まぁね、湊あくあを最近知ったよって人ね
Well, for those who recently got to know Minato Aqua
いてくれてると思うんだけれども
I think there are some of you here
まぁ昨年開催した「あくあ色スーパー☆ドリーム」っていう
Last year, I held "Aqua Iro Super Dream"...
8月に行ったソロライブが
a solo live in August
あるんだけれども
we had that, but...
今回「あくあ色すーぱーみらくる☆どり〜む♪」ということで
this time it's "Aqua Iro Super Miracle Dream"
まぁちょっと何かね、ソロライブのいいところだったり
So, like, taking the best parts of the solo live
こうつまみ食いして、ここ見てほしい、ここも...
picking bits and pieces, wanting you to see this and that...
見てほしい、全部見てほしいけど...みたいな感じのね、ショートバージョンで...
I want you to see it, I want you to see all of it... but like, this short version...
今回は、え、YouTubeのみんなにお届けできたらいいなって思ってます。
This time, I hope I can deliver it to everyone on YouTube.
ま、ワンマンライブに参加してくれたみんなもね、「あ、い、もう見なくていいじゃん」ってならないように...
Well, for everyone who participated in the one-man live, so you don't feel like 'Oh, I don't need to watch this anymore'...
新曲を用意しておりますので...
I have a new song prepared, so...
ちょっと頑張って覚えてきたから、よかったら最後まで見てね。よろしく！
I worked hard to learn it, so please watch until the end. Thank you!
ということで、あ、みんなね、コメントね、いっぱいしてくれてありがとうね。
So, anyway, oh, thanks everyone for all the comments.
じゃあね、あ、ちょっとね、あの、歌とかね、ちょっと歌うから、あんまり読むことはできないんですけれど...
So, I'm going to sing a bit, so I won't be able to read them all...
ちゃんと見てます！ありがとう、ありがとうね。
But I am looking! Thank you, thank you.
ということで、あ、そうだ。
So, anyway, oh, that's right.
この後ね、このライブの後の話になっちゃうんだけど...
This is about after the live, but...
ライブの後、えー、メンバー限定生放送で、えっと、3Dで、ちょっとね、あの、話したり...
After the live, there'll be a members-only livestream in 3D where we can talk...
ちょっとこのね、ライブの後の感想会したり、えっと、写真を撮ったりするのね。
We'll have an after-show talk and take some photos.
よかったらね、メンバーになってくれた人たちは一緒に見ましょう。
If you're a member, let's watch it together.
ぜひなってない人は今からなろう。よろしく頼む！
If you're not a member yet, join now! I'm counting on you!
今日なんか動きおかしいね。やばい、緊張してんのかも...。ははっ！
My movements are a bit weird today. Oh no, maybe I'm nervous... Haha!
はい、ということで、えー、それじゃあね、長々と話してしまいましたが...
Alright, well then, I've talked for a long time, but...
次の曲、行きたいと思います！
I'd like to go to the next song!
その前に、衣装チェンジ！
But before that, costume change!
あ、あ、あ、あ、あ...
Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah...
ということで、次の曲聴いてください。
So, please listen to the next song.
気まぐれロマンティック。
Kimagure Romantic.
ロマンティック 恋のアンテナは
Romantic, my love antenna is...
嵐で どこかへ飛んでいった
...flying away somewhere in the storm.
嘘でしょう 冷たくあしらった
No way, you treated me coldly...
こしあん配り棒に
...as if handing out bean paste.
ちょっと 心が揺れてる
My heart is shaking just a little.
本当は 本気で私を
Actually, you truly...
叱って くれる大事な人
...are the precious person who scolds me.
なんて 言ったらあいつは 得意気になるから
If I say that, he'll get all cocky,
もう褒めたりしない
so I won't praise him anymore.
退屈な 運命に飽き飽きしたの
I'm sick and tired of this boring fate.
知らない 言葉で解き放して
Set me free with words I don't know.
ねぇ ダーリン ダーリン 心の 扉を壊してよ
Hey, darling, darling, break down the door to my heart.
大切な ことは目を見て言って
Look me in the eye when you say something important.
あなたと ならば この街を抜け出せる
With you, I can escape this city.
今すぐ 連れ出して My Sweet Sweet Darling
Take me away right now, my sweet, sweet darling.
ドラマティック 笑顔の秘密は
Dramatic, the secret of my smile is...
誰だって 探し続けてる
...what everyone keeps searching for.
見上げた 空に描くの 幸せの形
Drawing the shape of happiness in the sky I looked up at.
そう 私らしくいたい
Yes, I want to be myself.
気まぐれな テンションで振り回すけど
I'll lead you around with my fickle tension,
この手は 必ず離さないで
but please never let go of this hand.
ねぇ ダーリン ダーリン 心の 扉を叩いてよ
Hey, darling, darling, knock on the door to my heart.
素直な 気持ちがあふれてゆく
Honest feelings are overflowing.
あなたと ならば 笑っていられるよ
With you, I can keep smiling.
今すぐ 駆け出すの My Sweet Sweet Darling
Running out right now, my sweet, sweet darling.
みんなー！アイドル衣装似合ってるかなー？
Everyone! Does this idol outfit suit me?
どうかな？可愛いかな？
What do you think? Is it cute?
ダーリン ダーリン きっと 私は掴めるよ
Darling, darling, I'm sure I can grasp it.
幸せの 意味に気づいてゆく
Beginning to realize the meaning of happiness.
あなたと ならば 明日を変えられる
With you, I can change tomorrow.
今すぐ 連れ出して My Sweet Sweet Darling
Take me away right now, my sweet, sweet darling.
...たり心の
...break the door of my heart.
扉を壊してよ
Break down the door to my heart.
大切なことは目を見て
Look me in the eye when you say...
言って
...the things that matter.
あなたとならばこの街を
If I'm with you, I can escape...
抜け出せる
...this city.
今すぐ連れ出して My Sweet Darling
Take me away right now, my sweet darling.
恋愛サーキュレーション
Renai Circulation
せーのっ！
One, two!
でもそんなんじゃだめ
But that's not good enough.
もうそんなんじゃほら
Look, that's just not gonna work.
心は進化するよもっともっと
My heart will keep evolving, more and more.
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If this is a relationship that'll vanish if voiced,
言葉を消せばいいやって
then I'll just have to erase the words.
思ってた 恐れてた
That's what I thought, and what I feared.
だけどあれ？なんか違うかも
But wait, maybe it's something different?
千里の道も一歩から
A journey of a thousand miles starts with one step.
石のように固いそんな意志で
With a will as firm as a stone,
ちりも積もれば大和撫子
dust piles up to become a Yamato Nadeshiko.
死ぬ気で いや、死ぬ気で！
I'll give it my all! No, I'll put my life on the line!
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Soft and light, floating and bright.
あなたが名前を呼ぶそれだけで宙に浮ぶ
Just hearing you call my name makes me float in the air.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Floating and bright, soft and light.
あなたが笑っているそれだけで笑顔になる
Just seeing you smile makes me smile too.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God,
運命のいたずらでも
even if it was a prank of fate,
めぐり逢えたことが
getting to meet you...
しあわせなの
...makes me so happy.
でもそんなんじゃだめ
But that's not good enough.
もうそんなんじゃほら
Look, that's just not gonna work.
心は進化するよもっともっと
My heart will keep evolving, more and more.
そうそんなんじゃやだ
No, I don't want it like that.
ねぇそんなんじゃまだ
Hey, it's not enough yet.
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
Please keep watching me, forever and ever.
私の中のあなたほど
Compared to how much you mean to me,
あなたの中の私の存在は
my existence within you...
まだまだ大きくないこともわかってるけれど
...isn't that big yet, I know that, but...
今この同じ瞬間
The fact that we're sharing...
共有してる実感
...this same moment right now,
ちりも積もれば大和撫子
dust piles up to become a Yamato Nadeshiko.
略してちりつも大和撫子！
In short, Chi-ri-tsu-mo Yamato Nadeshiko!
くらくらり くらくらる
Dizzy and dazed, head in a haze.
あなたを見上げたらそれだけでまぶしすぎて
Just looking up at you, you're so blindingly bright.
くらくらる くらくらり
Head in a haze, dizzy and dazed.
あなたを想っているそれだけで溶けてしまう
Just thinking about you makes me melt away.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God,
運命のいたずらでも
even if it was a prank of fate,
めぐり逢えたことが
getting to meet you...
しあわせなの
...makes me so happy.
恋する季節は欲張りサーキュレーション
The season of love is a greedy circulation.
恋する気持ちは欲張りサーキュレーション
The feeling of love is a greedy circulation.
恋する瞳は欲張りサーキュレーション
The eyes in love are a greedy circulation.
恋する乙女は欲張りサーキュレーション
The girl in love is a greedy circulation.
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Soft and light, floating and bright.
あなたが名前を呼ぶそれだけで宙に浮ぶ
Just hearing you call my name makes me float in the air.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Floating and bright, soft and light.
あなたが笑っているそれだけで笑顔になる
Just seeing you smile makes me smile too.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God,
運命のいたずらでも
even if it was a prank of fate,
めぐり逢えたことが
getting to meet you...
しあわせなの
...makes me so happy.
でもそんなんじゃだめ
But that's not good enough.
もうそんなんじゃほら
Look, that's just not gonna work.
心は進化するよもっともっと
My heart will keep evolving, more and more.
そうそんなんじゃやだ
No, I don't want it like that.
ねぇそんなんじゃまだ
Hey, it's not enough yet.
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
Please keep watching me, forever and ever.
しばらくお待ちください
Please wait a moment
あくあ色スーパーミラクルドリーム
Aqua Iro Super Miracle Dream
あくあ色に染まれ！
Dye it in Aqua's color!
君にBaby Sweet Berry Love
To you, Baby Sweet Berry Love
大人な気持ちだけ
Only adult feelings
分け合えたらいいのにな
I wish we could share them
願いを叶えてよ
Please make my wish come true
See you Tiffany-cha Give me Give me Shiny-tan
P-R-E-T-T-Y Tiny Tiny Berry Love
大好きなハートも
Even my favorite heart
ごめんねの涙も
And even my sorry tears
本当は素直に見せたくて
Honestly, I want to show them to you plainly
伝えたい想いと
The feelings I want to convey
裏返しの態度
And my contradictory attitude
上手になれない心模様
My heart's patterns that I can't manage well
どうして空回り 胸がギュッとなる
Why am I spinning my wheels, my chest feels tight
近い距離がもどかしいよね
Being this close is frustrating, isn't it?
届けたいな
I want to reach you
君とBaby Sweet Berry Love 一人きりじゃなくて
With you, Baby Sweet Berry Love, I'm not alone
でもね まっすぐに見つめて 空色映したい
But you know, look straight at me, I want to reflect the sky color
もっとBaby Sweet Berry Love せめて君の前では
More Baby Sweet Berry Love, at least in front of you
笑って 怒って 溢れた ありのままでいたい
Laughing, getting angry, overflowing, I want to be as I am
だからBaby Sweet Berry Love
So, Baby Sweet Berry Love
一緒に始めよう
Let's start together
See you Tiffany-cha Give me Give me Shiny-tan
P-R-E-T-T-Y Tiny Tiny Berry Love
閉じられたハートを
My closed heart
探してみるけれど
I try to search for it, but
本当は自分の一番奥にある
In truth, it's deep inside myself
まるで寂しげに
Just like a lonely
澄ました迷い猫
Clear-faced stray cat
こぼれた夕日に嫉妬しちゃう
I get jealous of the spilled sunset
不意な優しさに はしゃぐ胸の音
The sound of my heart frolicking at unexpected kindness
ドタバタとか カラフルでキュンと
Clattering or colorful and heart-thumping
満ちていくの
It's filling up
君とBaby Sweet Berry Love 矛盾だらけだけど
With you, Baby Sweet Berry Love, it's full of contradictions, but
大事であればあるほど 誤魔化してしまうの
The more important it is, the more I gloss it over
だけどBaby Sweet Berry Love 自分の心まで
But Baby Sweet Berry Love, even my own heart
分からない時は君と 確かめ合いたいな
When I don't understand, I want to confirm it with you
だからBaby Sweet Berry Love
So, Baby Sweet Berry Love
同じ場所にいたい
I want to be in the same place
君にBaby Sweet Berry Love 自分を守るように
To you, Baby Sweet Berry Love, as if protecting myself
大切なことがあるの こんなに近くに
There's something important, this close by
君とBaby Sweet Berry Love 一人きりじゃなくて
With you, Baby Sweet Berry Love, I'm not alone
でもね まっすぐに見つめて 空色映したい
But you know, look straight at me, I want to reflect the sky color
もっとBaby Sweet Berry Love せめて君の前では
More Baby Sweet Berry Love, at least in front of you
笑って 怒って 溢れた ありのままでいたい
Laughing, getting angry, overflowing, I want to be as I am
だからBaby Sweet Berry Love
So, Baby Sweet Berry Love
こんなに好きだよ
I love you this much
See you Tiffany-cha Give me Give me Shiny-tan
P-R-E-T-T-Y Tiny Tiny Berry Love
ずっとBaby Sweet Berry Love
Always Baby Sweet Berry Love
はーい！ということで、
Hi! So,
ここまで駆け抜けてお届けしていますが、
we've been running through this so far, but,
えー、みんなね、ついてこれてますか？
uh, everyone, are you keeping up?
ついてこれてる？みんな！
Are you keeping up? Everyone!
ヤッホー！見えてるー？
Yahoo! Can you see me?
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
あ、これはあの、素直な人にしか見えない、
Oh, this is, um,
あの、水です。飲めます。
the water that only honest people can see. I can drink it.
あー！
Ah!
回復した！
I've recovered!
ま、こういうのもね、ありということで。いいのいいのいいのいいのよ。
Well, this kind of thing happens. It's fine, it's fine.
ということで、もうね、なんと後半に入っている…
And so, believe it or not, we're already into the second half...
そうなんだけれども。なんかさ、さっき誰か来てなかった？
That's right. But you know, wasn't someone else here just now?
いたよね？なんか急にさ、なんか邪魔してきてた気がするんだけど。
Someone was here, right? I feel like someone suddenly came and got in the way.
ちょっとあれ誰だろうね？え、みんな分かった？今、分かった？
I wonder who that was? Did everyone notice? Did you?
ちょっと呼んでみる？みんな、あいつの名前、ちょっと覚えてる？
Should we try calling them? Do you all remember their name?
いくよ！呼ぶよ！
Here we go! I'm calling!
せーの！
One, two...!
ネコー！
NEKO!
N-E-K-O、ネコ！
N-E-K-O, NEKO!
あ、来た来た来た！ネコ来た！
Oh, they're here! Neko's here!
みんな、あ、ネコ来た。
Everyone, look, Neko's here.
嘘でしょ？
No way.
え、ネコ3D化しちゃったんだけど！
Neko actually got a 3D model!
私がもうね、ネコと言えばみたいな感じで、パーって適当に書いた落書きがですね…
This scribble that I just drew randomly, thinking "this is what a cat looks like"...
なんとここまで、3D化してしまいました！
...has actually been made into 3D!
やめてなんか、すごい、すごいなんか気持ち悪い動きして。
Stop it! Those movements are so... so gross.
ねぇやめてよマジで。
Seriously, stop it.
気持ち悪いんだ動きが。なんかニョーンニョーンニョーンみたいな動きしてない？
Those movements are so creepy. They're all wobbly and weird.
一緒にね、さっき『恋愛サーキュレーション』をね、踊りましたけれども。
We just danced "Renai Circulation" together earlier.
ねぇ、可愛いねめっちゃ。
Hey, they're actually really cute.
実はね、なんと、ここにみんなにお知らせがあります！
Actually, I have an announcement for everyone!
なんとですね、ま、このね、3Dにもなったネコ…
Believe it or not... this Neko who just went 3D...
そして、新衣装でもね、あの、次の新衣装でもね、実はね、あのネコね、こうやって抱えて、頭に乗ってたりしている…
...and who I'm holding or who's on my head in my new outfit...
あの、ネコ！
...that Neko!
なんとですね、ずっとね、言われてたんだよ。「ネコのぬいぐるみ早く出ないの？」って。
People have been asking me forever: "When is the Neko plushie coming out?"
出ます！なんと！
It's coming out! For real!
「ネコビックぬいぐるみ」…これ正式名称であってるのかな？
"Neko Big Plushie"... I wonder if that's the official name?
わぁー！なんと作ることになりました！イエーイ！
Whoa! We're actually making them! Yay!
わぁー！ちょ、邪魔してこないで。入ってこないで。入ってくんなネコ！
Whoa! Hey, stop bothering me. Stay out of the frame. Get out of here, Neko!
やった！やったよ！商品化だよ、ネコ！マジで。
We did it! You're being merchandised, Neko! Seriously.
あんた、出世したね！
You've really made it big!
はい、ということでね、詳細はライブの後に発表されますので…
So, the details will be announced after the live...
ぜひチェックしてください！お願いします！
So please be sure to check it out! Thank you!
お願いします！
Thank you!
ということでね、じゃあネコ、まだね、ちょっと歌うから…
Anyway, Neko... I'm going to sing some more...
控え室で待ってて。うん。
...so go wait in the green room. Okay.
じゃあね、バイバイ！バイバイ！
See ya! Bye-bye!
じゃあね！
See you!
素直に去っていったよ。
They left without a fuss.
ということで、じゃあね、後半戦まだまだ続きますけれども…
So, the second half of the show continues...
早速歌っていこうかなと思います！
I think it's time to start singing!
それでは、聞いてください。みんなへの思いを込めて、2曲続けて歌います。
Now, please listen. I'll be singing two songs in a row, dedicated to all of you.
聞いてください。『君色シグナル』。
Please listen to "Kimi-iro Signal".
君色シグナル
Kimi-iro Signal
放課後　二人で過ごした教室
The classroom where the two of us spent time after school
机の上　夢中で弾む君の声
On top of the desk, your voice bounces enthusiastically
鈍感な君のその態度が
That dense attitude of yours...
いつも私を　いじわるにさせるの
...always makes me want to be mean to you.
独りぼっちだと思った時もある
There were times when I felt all alone
涙　止められない日もある
And days when I couldn't stop my tears
本当の私を見つめてほしいの
I want you to look at the real me
きっと伝わると
Believing that surely...
信じているよ
...my feelings will reach you.
君はいつだって　いつだって変わらないから
Because you're always, always the same
私が何回も何回も　シグナル送ってあげる
I'll send you signals over and over again
夢見たあの丘目指して
Aiming for that hill we dreamed of
挫けそうな時も　頑張れそうだよ
Even when I'm about to give up, I feel like I can keep going
君がいるから
Because you are here.
ふたり歩くいつもの帰り道
The usual way home we walk together.
名前はない気持ちが芽生え始めてる
A feeling without a name is starting to sprout.
だけど踏み出すための勇気は
But the courage to take a step forward...
少しだけまだ遠くにある
...is still a little bit out of reach.
何も持っていなかった私に
To me, who had nothing...
君がくれた心の鍵は
...the key to my heart that you gave me...
胸の奥で眠ってた蕾に
...to the bud that was sleeping deep in my chest...
春の日差しを届けてくれる
...it brings the spring sunlight.
君をいつだっていつだって想ってるから
Because I'm always, always thinking of you.
きっといつの日かいつの日かちゃんとわかってほしい
I hope that one day, one day, you'll truly understand.
ふたりで描いた未来を
The future we drew together...
もっと近い距離で見つめられるように夢見てるから
...I'm dreaming so we can gaze at it from closer range.
みんなのおかげで、こうやって夢だった3Dライブやることができました！
Thanks to everyone, I was able to perform this 3D live, which was my dream!
本当にみんなありがとね！
Thank you so much, everyone!
これからも、みんなどうぞ湊あくあのことよろしくお願いします！
From now on as well, please continue to support Minato Aqua!
ライブはまだまだ終わらないけど、よかったら最後まで見てくれると嬉しいです！
The live isn't over yet, but I'd be happy if you could watch until the end!
あの日触れた君のシグナル
Your signal that I touched that day.
始まりの扉が開くよ
The door to the beginning is opening.
あのね、
You know...
君はいつだっていつだって変わらないでね
Please don't ever, ever change.
私に何回も何回もシグナル送ってほしい
I want you to send me signals over and over again.
輝くあの虹のように
Like that shining rainbow...
涙のあとも奇跡に変えるよ
...I'll turn even the traces of tears into a miracle.
君はいつだっていつだって変わらないから
Because you never, ever change...
私が何回も何回もシグナル送ってあげる
...I'll send you signals over and over again.
夢見たあの背中目指して
Aiming for that back I dreamed of...
挫けそうな時も頑張れそうだよ君がいるから
...even when I'm about to give up, I feel like I can do my best because you're here.
すき
I love you.
付かず離れずの毎日
Every day, neither too close nor too far.
退屈なんてないけど
There's no boredom, but...
胸の痛み苦しくて泣きたい時もある
...sometimes the pain in my chest is so hard I want to cry.
些細な出来事さえも
Even the most trivial events...
特別だって思うよ
...I think they're special.
ほらね今も君のこと考えちゃうの
See, even now, I find myself thinking of you.
好きと嫌い交互に数えていく占い
A fortune-telling counting "like" and "dislike" alternately.
2分の1の確率踏み出せないね
A one-in-two chance, I just can't take that step.
君と大空見上げたら
When I look up at the vast sky with you...
この気持ちだって言えるかな
...I wonder if I can express these feelings.
一つ一つ言葉にしよう
I'll put them into words, one by one.
笑って聞いてくれたなら
If you listen with a smile...
きっとああこの関係はアイマイモコっていうのかな
...then surely, I wonder if this relationship is what's called 'Aimaimoko'.
つれづれでも I wish, I feel my sweet 大切にしなくちゃ
Even in weariness, I wish, I feel my sweet, I have to cherish it.
恋の仕方を説いても 正解なんてないでしょう
Even if you explain how to love, there's no right answer, right?
君の気持ちヒントさえ見つからないよ
I can't even find a hint of your feelings.
好きの二文字何度も 頭の中唱える
The word 'love,' I chant it in my head over and over.
秘密の想いは 伝わらないね
My secret feelings don't reach you, do they?
君と今 空に描こう カラフルになったこの日々を
Let's draw in the sky with you now, these days that have become colorful.
鮮やかさが生まれてくよ 笑って泣いて胸の中
Vividness is being born, laughing and crying inside my chest.
きっと ああ この感情が アイマイモコって言うのなら
Surely, ah, if this feeling is called 'aimaimoko'...
つれづれでも I wish I feel myself 大切にしたいな
...even in idleness, I wish, I feel myself, I want to cherish it.
すれ違う道も 離れてく距離も 向き合って心を開けたら
Even passing paths or growing distances, if we could face each other and open our hearts...
勇気を出して前に進めるさ
...we can take courage and move forward.
心にそっと 触れるよ
I'll gently touch your heart.
君と今 空見上げたら 素直に好きと言えるかな
If I look up at the sky with you now, I wonder if I can say 'I love you' honestly.
君の側で笑う未来 願ってたくて
I want to wish for a future where I laugh by your side.
ねぇ きっと ああ この関係が アイマイモコって言うのかな
Hey, surely, ah, is this relationship called 'aimaimoko'?
つれづれでも I wish I feel myself 大切にしなくちゃ
Even in idleness, I wish, I feel myself, I have to cherish it.
いつか届くなら
If it reaches you someday.
すき
I love you.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
や、ねー。3Dライブ、本当に楽しかったです！
Wow. This 3D live was really fun!
またね、3Dライブやりたいと思ってるから
I'm thinking of doing another 3D live again...
よかったらまた、歌見に来てくれると嬉しいなって思ってるよ！
...so I'd be happy if you could come see me sing again!
よろしくねー！
Thank you!
ということで、今日はね、みんな本当に最後まで見てくださり、ありがとうございました！
So, thank you all so much for watching until the very end today!
このあとすぐ、なんと告知はね、されてますけれども
Right after this, well, an announcement has already been made...
メンバー限定生放送で、湊あくあ3Dメン限配信がありますので
...there will be a Minato Aqua 3D members-only stream on a member-exclusive live broadcast...
よかったらね、メンバー限定、メンバー登録もよろしくお願いします！ よろしくー！
...so please consider registering for the membership! Thank you!
ということで、最後とは言いましたけどあと一曲あります！
So, I said it was the last, but there's one more song!
あと一曲あります！
There's one more song!
ということで、それではね、最後の曲はやっぱりあの曲で終わっていきたいと思います！
So, I'd like to end with that song for the last one after all!
ということで、最後の曲聴いてください
So, please listen to the last song.
あくあ色ぱれっと
Aqua Iro Palette.
何をしても不器用で 何かとミスしてばっかだった
No matter what I did, I was clumsy and just kept making mistakes.
ダメダメな私だって できることがあるの
Even a useless person like me has things I can do.
へこんで悲しくたって 笑顔にしてあげるんだ
Even if I'm depressed and sad, I'll make you smile.
ここにいるから早く 私を見つけてね
I'm right here, so find me quickly.
Love you! Love you! Oh-oh-oh!
Love you! Love you! Oh-oh-oh! 愛してるもっと
Love you! Love you! Oh-oh-oh! I love you more.
いつでも隣にいるし いつでも一緒に笑える
I'm always by your side, and we can always laugh together.
私をたくさん知って たくさん好きって言って
Get to know me a lot, and tell me you love me a lot.
わがままで朝も苦手
I'm selfish and not good with mornings.
どじだしたメタメタだけど
I've become a bit clumsy and messy, but...
それでも私のことを見ててね
...still, please keep watching me.
描く夢の
Of the dreams I draw,
未来へ続く道を
the path leading to the future...
君と歩けますように
I hope I can walk it with you.
ねぇもっと好きになってもらいたいの
Hey, I want you to like me more.
頭の中は君ばっかてやば
My head is filled with only you, it's crazy.
そっぽなんて向いてないであーもうヤキモキしちゃうわ
Don't look away, oh geez, I'm getting impatient.
あーあ
Ah-ah...
ずっとずっと好きがいいの
I want to be liked forever and ever.
心の奥もトキめいちゃうくらいに
So much that even the depths of my heart throb.
こっち向いててよ四六時中
Look this way, twenty-four seven.
あーもう離さないから絶対に
Ah, I'll never let go, absolutely.
LOVE YOU LOVE YOU OH OH OH OH
I LOVE YOU OH OH OH OH
愛してるもっと
I love you more.
君がいるから私
Because you're here, I...
いつでも頑張れるんだ
...can always do my best.
落ち込んで悲しくたって
Even if I'm feeling down and sad,
君がいるから
because you're here.
みんな！今日は3Dライブ来てくれて本当にありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you so much for coming to the 3D live today!
最後まであくあ色に染まれー！
Be dyed in Aqua's color until the very end!
君がいるから歩いてこれた
I've been able to walk this far because you're here.
君がいなくちゃ前も見れない
Without you, I can't even see ahead.
嫌なこととか辛いこととかあったって
Even when there were bad things or painful things,
君の力でここまで笑ってこれたんだ
I've been able to come this far laughing thanks to your strength.
今度はもっと私がグッと引っ張って
This time, I'll pull you along even more
連れて行くんだ
and take you with me.
君がいるから私がいるの
I exist because you're here.
こんな私を
Someone like me,
愛してくれるね
you'll love me, right?
もっともっとまだまだ受け止めてよねー
More and more, keep accepting me, okay?
さぁ声を上げて
Now, raise your voice!
ねぇもっとねぇもっと
Hey more, hey more!
好きになってもらいたいの
I want you to like me more.
いつでもそう私ばっか見てたい
I want to look only at me all the time.
そっぽなんて向かせないわ
I won't let you look away,
ねぇほら夢中にしちゃうわ
hey look, I'll make you obsessed.
あーあ
Ah-ah...
ずっとずっと好きがいいの
I want to be liked forever and ever.
心も体も染まっちゃうくらいに
So much that your heart and body are dyed.
こっち向いててよ四六時中
Look this way, twenty-four seven.
あーもう離さないから絶対に
Ah, I'll never let go, absolutely.
絶対ね
Definitely,
絶対よ
I mean it!
約束ー！
Promise!
I LOVE YOU OH OH OH OH
愛しちゃうもっと
I'll love you more.
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
湊あくあ 3Dライブ 2021
あくあ色 すーぱーみらくる どり〜む♪
Minato Aqua 3D Live 2021
Aqua Iro Super Miracle Dream
皆さんどうもこんあくあー！湊あくあでーす！
Hello everyone, Kon-Aqua! I'm Minato Aqua!
ということで、「あくあ色すーぱーみらくる☆どり〜む♪」楽しんでいただけましたか？
So, did you enjoy "Aqua Iro Super Miracle Dream"?
当日の彼女はきっと緊張して
I think she on that day is probably so nervous...
胃が張り裂けそうな気持ちになっていると思うので、よかったら温かいコメントいっぱいしてくれたら嬉しいです！
...that her stomach feels like it's going to burst, so I'd be happy if you could leave lots of warm comments!
て終わってんのかもう。ははっ
Wait, is it over already? Haha.
ということで、ここからは告知タイム！
So, from here it's announcement time!
重大告知もあるので、よかったら最後までお見逃しなく！
There are major announcements too, so please don't miss out until the end!
それじゃあ告知その一、行ってみましょう。デデン！
Then, let's go with announcement number one. Ta-da!
NEKO BIG ぬいぐるみ
5月9日販売開始
NEKO BIG Plushie
Sales start May 9th
先ほど3Dライブで出てきた「NEKO」3D化を記念して
To commemorate the 3D-ification of "NEKO" that appeared in the 3D live just now...
「NEKO BIGぬいぐるみ」が遂に発売されます！
...the "NEKO BIG Plushie" is finally being released!
全長約45cm。約45... あれ？「約」ってなんだろう。うーん。
Total length approx. 45cm. Approx. 45... wait? I wonder what "approx" means. Hmm.
ということで、こちらは概要欄より購入できますので...
So, you can purchase this from the description section...
よろしかったら購入、チェックチェック！
If you'd like, please buy it and check it out!
一緒に遊ぶもよし、お散歩に連れてくもよし、
It's fine to play together, or take it for a walk,
寝るもよし、殴るはちょっと
fine to sleep with, but as for hitting it...
やめてほしいけど、まあ、抱きかかえるならよし。
I'd like you to stop, but hugging is fine.
いっぱい使ってね！
Please use it a lot!
告知その２、デデン！
Announcement number two, ta-da!
湊あくあ新作歌ってみたが、ついに解禁！
Minato Aqua's new cover video is finally released!
このあとすぐ！マジ！
Coming right after this! Seriously!
にゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃ…
Nyanyanvanyanvanyanya...
どんな動画になっているかちょっと分からないと思うけどね、
I think you might not know what kind of video it is, but...
みんなよかったら見てね。このあとすぐだよ。
everyone please watch it if you like. It's coming right after this.
絶対見てね、絶対だよ、絶対だよ、絶対だからね！
Make sure to watch it, definitely, definitely, I mean it!
続いて、その３！
Next, number three!
こちらもこのあとすぐ！えー、メンバー限定で
This is also coming right after this! Uh, for members only,
初めての3D配信も行いたいと思います！イエーイ！
I'll be doing my first 3D stream! Yay!
プリンセスな衣装で撮影会をしたりとか、
I'll do a photoshoot in my princess dress,
あとまあ感想を話したりとか、ちょっと色々お話したり、
and talk about my impressions, and various other things,
えっとーしようと思ってるので、よかったらみんな、メンバーシップ限定生放送見に来てくれると嬉しいです！
so I'd be happy if everyone came to see the member-only live stream!
まだメンバーシップになってないよって方、今がチャンスです。
For those who aren't members yet, now is your chance.
よかったらメンバーシップの登録、概要欄からできるので登録してってね！
You can join the membership from the description, so please sign up!
みんな、あくあ色に染まれー！！
Everyone, be dyed in Aqua's color!!
そしてそしてそして！重大告知、行きます！
And and and! Major announcement, here it goes!
デデデン！
Ta-da!
湊あくあ、2021年8月8日デビュー3周年を記念して、
Minato Aqua, to celebrate her 3rd anniversary on August 8, 2021,
YouTube無料ライブ第2弾開催決定！イエーイ！
the 2nd free YouTube live has been decided! Yay!
ということで配信日などは追ってお知らせするので、よかったらお待ちください！
So, I'll announce the stream date later, please look forward to it!
ちょっとね、『あくあ色すーぱーみらくる☆どり〜む♪』とはまた
I'm thinking of making it a different kind of live from
違った感じのライブにしたいなーって考えてるから、楽しみにしててね！
'Aqua Iro Super Miracle Dream,' so please stay tuned!
それじゃあ、本当の本当に、最後までライブ見てくれてありがとう！
Well then, for real for real, thank you for watching the live until the end!
以上、湊あくあでした！バイバーイ！
That's all from Minato Aqua! Bye-bye!
ん〜まっ！
*Kiss*
最後まで見てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for watching until the end!